Guide to the KSFO Collection ARS.0063
Archive of Recorded Sound
KSFO Collection
1953-1989
ARS.0063
KSFO (Radio station: San Francisco, Calif.)
36 boxes
Archive of Recorded Sound
The KSFO collection consists of audiovisual material and ephemera from this San Francisco radio station's years owned by Golden West Broadcasting, 1956-1983. KSFO was known for their news and sports coverage, as well as the voice talents of such personalities as Don Sherwood, Russ Hodges, Lon Simmons, and Al "Jazzbo" Collins. The majority of this collection involves station marketing, promotions, and fundraisers, although there are airchecks and other broadcast recordings. Production library material includes jingles, themes, music beds, promotional spots, and advertising.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The KSFO Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by KSFO in June, 1998.
Scope and Contents
Though it originally went on the air in 1925, the era of radio station KSFO covered in this collection is largely from 1956-1983, when the station was owned by Gene Autry's Golden West Broadcasters. Besides airing popular music, jazz, and nostalgia, KSFO provided the San Francisco Bay Area with news, sports, and other programming with cosmopolitan flair. Notable broadcast personalities at the station included Don Sherwood, Jim Lange, John Gilliland, Gene Nelson, Al "Jazzbo" Collins, Wally King, Herb Kennedy, Jack Carney, Del Courtney, Dan Sorkin, Terry McGovern, and Carter B. Smith. Legendary sportscasters Russ Hodges and Lon Simmons spent much of the 1960's on KSFO, announcing games for the San Francisco Giants and the San Francisco 49ers as well as Oakland Athletics baseball and Stanford University football. A few airchecks of these broadcasts are part of the collection. However, the majority of the audio found here is from KSFO's production library. This library, maintained on open reel tape, consists of jingles, IDs, music beds, advertising, and featured programming (such as the Mike Powell 5:30 Report) in various forms and versions, although airchecks and related recordings (often marked "Save") are present. KSFO's famous theme song "Sound of the City" exists in multiple iterations, as do recordings of "Bye Bye Baby," the opening music for San Francisco Giants baseball broadcasts, inspired by Russ Hodges' catch-phrase. Singer Mel Tormé lent his signature "velvet fog" croon for station identification, and there are several reels featuring his voice here. The Commercial Vault was KSFO's own name for a series of tapes documenting notable ads as originally broadcast on the station. Although incomplete, it remains a fascinating record of local music-related advertising in the 1960s and 70s. There is also a series titled Promo Vault, which archives the station's promotional campaign spots during the same period. KSFO jingles and other advertising and marketing were produced both in-house and by other companies. There is some content pertaining to management, but very little documentation regarding the internal workings of the station. Almost all printed matter in this collection was originally distributed to the public in one form or another. The collection also contains material from other stations, particularly KYA. In 1983, KSFO was sold to King Radio Broadcasting, which had already owned KYA. It appears that with all the changes in ownership, material from different stations has been intermingled. It would also appear that, due to the overwhelming volume of promotional material, it is likely that much of this collection is derived from KSFO's promotions department. One way for the station to promote itself was through fundraising campaigns. Among the several events KSFO organized, the United Crusades and Police Athletic League games are generously represented in a variety of media. Other contemporary events covered in recordings include news of the John F. Kennedy assassination, Dan White on KRON in 1979, and commentary from S.I. Hayakawa during the student strike at San Francisco State University in 1968. Physical media in the KSFO collection is primarily audio on tape (around 650 objects), with some video (largely U-Matic cassettes), 16mm film (four reels), photographs, slides, and ephemera (eight scrapbooks of printed matter).
Arrangement
Original order has been retained.
Indexing Terms
Hodges, Russ; KSFO (Radio station: San Francisco, Calif.).; Oakland Athletics (Baseball team).; San Francisco 49ers (Football team).; San Francisco Giants (Baseball team).; Sherwood, Don, 1925-1983; Simmons, Lon; Tormé, Mel, 1925-1999; Radio stations.; San Francisco Bay Area (Calif.)
- Series 1. Audio
  - Miscellaneous
    - promos, airchecks, etc., 1958-1978 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      KYA recreated dance remote w/Paul Pendarvis Orch. 1958; baseball promos, highlights; Giants promos 1960 (with script), 1978, etc.; 49ers promo 1962; Tom Campbell KYA 1969; Scott Thomas last half hour on KYA 1970; Russ Hodges promos, samples; Lon Simmons Sports Show promos 10/3/1958.
    - jingles, promos, etc., 1959-1982 (Box 3)
      KYA Memories; KYA jingles 1977, 1983; People Power 1/9/74; KOIT, K106 1971; KMPC New Home Dedication 1968; Beatles Christmas promo 12/23/77; Torme KSFO jingles 4/22/63; Pied Piper promos; KYA People Power /Ecology/Anti-Drug; KUSF Woody Guthrie California Travelin'; Arbo and Al #2 12/2/59; KSFO Looney Sounds; Casablanca lines (with script); KYA A'Go Go master; KYA series 31, 32, 38, 40; KYA Firesign Theatre bits 10/82; KYA ID Separator
    - airchecks, features, jingles, etc., 1969-1979 (Box 4)
      A-1 & A-2 4/12/71; Rock Years 1-4; Mark Taylor, Pete Cooney aircheck; Pat Williams KSFO 7/29/69; RG3; Pete Scott - Russ Hodges and Lon Simmons Stories; Oldies- Save 1979; Classic Gold; KYA Drug Rap; Steve Jordan; Operation Undercover; KSFO Marpet jingles 4/24/69
    - jingles, features, etc., 1961-1976 (Box 5)
      KOIT New Country; BLORE jingle; PAMS master; KSFO News Thanksgiving 1961; MLK "I Have a Dream"; Art Fine "A Chance to Chase A Dream" 11/5/1976; KSFO 1962 Headlines Awards
    - jingles, promos, features, news, etc., 1964-1983 (Box 6)
      49ers; KSFO police announcements; McQuade Award 1965; California State Fair Broadcast Awards Submission 1967; KYA-FM production jingle music beds 1983; Hayakawa editorial 12/2/68; It Seems to Me; KYA Christmas Package; KRON Bye Bye Baby 1972; Blake Freeway Opposition 10/7/64; Al White San Francisco; KSFO Moog Theme; KSFO This Date in Baseball History 4/19/81; Baseball promos 1974; KYA-FM Playdate series 1983; KYA DJ cuts 8/9/76; KYA shotguns; Stanford Football Music "All Right Now"; KSFO/Giants Mike Ivie Grand Slam; Ted Taylor Copter Reports; Wally King on Mesnick-Richmond Incident 2/11/64; KSFO weekend beds; Giants Old BB stuff Mays Save; KSFO IDs 1977; Old KYA Jingle; Security Pacific Music for Stanford; FB 1983; Miss Miller audition; KYA-FM IDs for 1973-74; Music cuts McNeal, Stone, Hardy, O'Quinn; KYA People Power jingle; KSFO Loves You; Bye Bye Baby Voc. and Inst.; Jerelee and Niles 6/24/66; A's Profiles; Michelle Hughes; A's promos 1981
    - KYA jingles, etc., 1976 (Box 7)
      Random Golden Bells; KYA Clark & Mason; 1260 Time Capsule; KYA jingles; KYA Jack Bryan; KYA Happy New Year 1976
    - Christmas Kids 1981 (Box 8)
    - airchecks, features, news, promos, etc., 1962-1981 (Box 10)
      Chris Edwards and The Osmonds; Black History Minutes; Lombard Lafayette/Chris Cane 1975-76; Laff Off 1,2; Some Things We Missed On the 40s; KMPC Sounders; Delay Loops; Giants, Airport Stuff aircheck 10/3/62; Airport 12/27/70; Oakland A's Highlights 1981; KSFO Marpet beds 4/24/1969
    - airchecks, features, news, etc., 1954-1984 (Box 11)
      Could This be You? KVI Seattle 1954-56; A's Profiles; Mike Powell 5:30 Report airchecks 1/16/70, 10/2/74, 3/14/75; Scott Carpenter Orbital Flight 5/24/62; Raymond Burr - Policeman; KSFO News Golden Gate Rapid Transit; KSFO News Berlin Special Report 1961; Coleen Moore on Mike Powell 12/71; Jeno Paulucci on Mike Powell 4/72; Beneficial Presentation 9/5/65; 40s Media Demo; William O. Douglas Speech, Palace Hotel 4/17/61; KSFO News 8/61; Dick Whittington 4/29/59; Lem Brothers bed; Dr. Robert Wesson, Nicaragua Today, Commonwealth Club 2/10/84; Mays Homer; Haiku Contest; Musical! Weekend 5/26-27/84; Giants promo audiocassettes 1978
    - promos, commercials, etc., 1975-1984 (Box 12)
      Ted Reed, Nightside; Leo Burnett Chicago 1984; John Lennon promo 12/3/81; Demos 1974; KSBW Salinas; Mervyn's Christmas Sale 11/24/75; Dentyne; Could This Be You? KVI; KSFO Hudson and Landry; Bridges Edited Choir; Mel Tormé
    - airchecks, news ,features, etc., 1961-1968 (Box 17)
      News Archives; News Master 1967-68; KSFO News Special Report- Corte Madera Holdup/Shooting 10/19/61; KSFO News Rapid Transit 7/24/62; Kennedy Assassination Coverage 11/22/63; Bogges aircheck; Santa Reports 1961
    - news, airchecks, features, promos, etc., 1955-1974 (Box 18)
      Mayor Alioto Commute; KGBS aircheck 2/1/72; KVI Presentation; Cancer Cure, Highway Patrol; Gavin Presentation; Golden West Broadcasting Focus Group 7/15/74; North Pole Exclusives; Love Power Contest; The Black Mass "Rats In The Wall" KPFA Berkeley 1964; Black History series; Winners Work; Santa Central 1966; jackhammer noise in front of studio 1955-56; Hawaii Aircheck Winners; S.O.B. Presentation; Bill Guyman For Sherwood Show.
    - jingles, promos, presentations, airchecks, etc., 1962-1984 (Box 20)
      Del Courtney and Russ Hodges Baseball promos, facts 2/27/62; Baseball network promos; Baseball Facts with Russ 3/6/62; Xmas promo 1965; Vic Ives aircheck 3/20/72; Xmas with Kids; Phil Brooks WKPA aircheck; Major Market Radio (MMR) presentation 7/66; KSFO Loves You promos 1968; Allen Sherman Now Bow; KSFO KMPC KVI promos; News return cues (typewriter andamp; telephone) 1963; KEX jingle package; KSFO Spirit jingle; KVI jingles; Phone Calls promos; Juanita Beasley promos; The Farley promos; KSFO Kids at Christmas; Trojan Horse spots; Man on Matson Deck; KMPC, Golden West Broadcasters presentation; People Package 1974; Impact presentation 1975; Way Out 1974
    - promos, sportscasts, presentations, etc., 1956-1978 (Box 21)
      Audio: 49ers promo 4/18/57; 49ers presentation 1978; Giants vs. Pittsburgh 6/18/59; "Giants score 5 runs in here somewhere"; "homer - save"; Hodges/Simmons 8/11/56; 49ers vs. Baltimore Winning TD 11/27/60; Lon Simmons Giants promos 1/19/58; Baseball preview by Joe Hasel, WNEW; Hodges, Carney 2/15/68; Simmons 49er promos 1958; 49er Highlights 1961, 1977, 1978; Hawaii Winners; 49ers 9/12/59 #2; 49er Shorties 1957; Carney "I'm With You" promos; Armour presentation 1965; Kaleidoscope promos 3/16/64; Sounds of MMR presentation; KSTO Giants/Happy Days 1978
    - KSFO Marpet (1/2" tape), 1969-04-29 (Box 22)
    - Bay To Breakers Theme, jingles, promos, etc., 1959-1984 (Box 23)
      Bay To Breakers Theme 4/16/84; KSFO stereo copy 1959-1961; You Can Feel It All Over jingles; KYA People Power 1974; KYA Custom Grid 1and2
    - jingles, promos, sportscasts, etc., 1959-1985 (Box 24)
      Giants vs. Reds 6/27/79; KYA Silvertree jingles; Lange, Sounds of SF; KYA PAMS 1971, etc.; Hotlen jingles; KSFO Spirit jingles; Disneyland, "Bad Bad Softball"; KSFO Loves You; KYA Custom Grid 3; Oneders 1974; AVCO Overground; KYA Christmas 1979; New Station IDs 1966; Production Music; Space Stuff; KFRC Close Encounters logo; A's Fan jingle; KSFO promos 1976-77; 49ers Football promo 1979; Stanford promo; Master Music Tape R; KSFO jingles 1983; KYA jingle master with themes (Drake, Syracuse, Tripp, Mitchell, Donahue, Saunders, House Party, Nelson, Washburne); Dubs From Music Carts; Omnimusic 1985; Giants vs. Milwaukee 9/1959; Sounds Effects
    - Angels, Giants Update (Technicolor Sound Movie cartridge), 1976 (Box 25)
    - Mike Powell Reports, news, promos, etc., 1961-1983 (Box 26)
      Mike Powell 5:30 Reports: Tennessee Ernie Ford #1, The Exceptional Child 12/74, The Right to Learn 6/76, Sportsworld 2/76, State of the Fourth Estate 1/76, Alioto at the Press Club 1/76, Vietnam and The American Economy 2/76, George Moscone 10/77, Report #5 Dear Hearts; Mini-Docs: Jane Fonda 3-4/76, Women and Alcoholism 1975, Public Trust/Private Trust 8/77; News Special Reports: Hale Hotel Fire 1/3/62, Berlin 10/12/61, Corte Madera holdup 10/19/61; Alcoholism special; We're People, You're People; Super Frog; The Story of Old San Francisco 1/83; Olympic/Kendall spots 1976; Pierce-Paebco 12/24/68; A's Highlights, Theme Music Billboards 1983; Sherwood Baseball promos
  - Commercial Vault
    Advertising for local businesses, many of which are music-related: Tower Records and other record stores, concerts at venues such as the Fillmore, Family Dog, Winterland, Avalon, Cow Palace, and live performances by such artists as The Temptations, The Bee Gees, Jimi Hendrix and Santana.
    - Comm. Vault # 3 ,7, 13, 18, 19, 26, 1968-1971 (Box 40)
    - Comm. Vault #11, 12, 16, 29, 38, 41, 1969-1973 (Box 23)
    - Comm. Vault #37-57, 1972-1974 (Box 14)
    - Comm. Vault #58-67, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Promotion Vault
    KSFO jingles, themes, and promotional spots.
    - Promo Vault #1-12,15, 23-25, 35-38, 41-43, 50, 51, 1969-1978 (Box 16)
    - Promo Vault #13, 16-22, 26-34, 40, 45, 1972-1977 (Box 22)
    - Promo Vault #14, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Promo Vault #46, 47, 52 (x2), 55-57, 1977-1979 (Box 23)
- Series 2. Video and Film
  - KSFO promos, Tour de Blah, 1969-1983 (Box 2)
    KSFO promos for KBHK/KRON 1969-1972; "Tour De Blah" 1983
  - KSFO promos, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
  - KSFO 11/17/70, 8/2/72, 8/30/72, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - KSFO, KYA promos, etc., 1970-1985 (Box 9)
    KSFO 8/30/72; Loves You spots 10/28/70; Jack Carney 10/22/69; Carter B. Smith; Football promo 11/13/70; sports 10/30/70; Terry McGovern 1/29/73; 560 KSFO/93 KYA 1985; WMJI Floating Records; Lawrence, Bay to Breakers
  - KSFO spots, KRON jingles, Christmas, etc., 1972-1981 (Box 12)
    KSFO Scott, MacGarvin, Breakthrough 7/13/74; KSFO 1972; Jingle Bells/KRON jingles 1981
  - KYA commercials, promos, airchecks, etc., 1980-1983 (Box 13)
    How To Use Reach and Frequency in Media Planning; VALS Typology; KYA Demo 1983; KINK 10/19/81; 13 Key Media Concepts; Airchecks; KYA Oldies Road Show; KYA Rock/60s ads 1981; jingles 1982; promo 1980; radio test tape; Media Touch Systems
  - demo, spots, ads, etc., 1979-1987 (Box 15)
    KYA Rock/60s ads 1979-1981; Gene Nelson, KHOS spots; KSFO Sales Tape demo; Ancil Payne Farewell 1987
  - KYA, KLHT, KSFO, 1981-1983 (Box 21)
    KYA/K-Lite home movies 7/20/82; KLHT Son of Music 4/21/83; KSFO Radio; KYA Gene Nelson 1982; KYA on Peninsula Weekly 11/81
  - promos, presentations, Tour de Blah, Bay to Breakers, 1981-1985 (Box 25)
    KLHT 7 Days 2/11/82; KYA/KLHT spots; Recruiting, Corporate Presentations; VALS Reports from SRI 1981-1982; KSFO/KYA Tour de Blah worktape 1985; Bay to Breakers Highlight Program
  - News, ads, promos, gag reel, etc., 1979-1984 (Box 27)
    KYA Jitterbug final 1/27/84; KLTH 20 sec.; K-Lite Primate Test; KYA Radio History of Rock and Roll 6/13/81; KSFO/KYA 1985; KSFO 1/30/81; Focus Testing TV Spots; King TV Spots; KYA 3/28/80, 6/9/81; KLTH Gag Reel 2/82; KYA Dan White/KRON 4/19/79
  - Film: KSFO Union Square (see also boxes 6 and 19); Pop Chronicles (Box 8)
  - Film: Angels, Giants KMPC, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Film: KSFO "Morti" and United Crusade in Union Square, 1964 (Box 6)
    KSFO "Morti" color; "Union Square" black and white [United Crusade 1964, see photos in Box 19]
- Series 3. Photographs, Negatives, and Slides
  - Main Photofile: photographs, contact sheets, negatives, slides (some correspondence and memoranda included), 1962-1983 (Box 19)
    Photo File: Lon Simmons and Bill King; News, Sports Departments (includes Hal Lewis/J. Akuhead Pupule, Willie Mays, Nat Cole, etc.); Simmons and Hodges; DJs- Baseball promo; News Staff 7/67; Russ, Bill, Lon- Giants; Giants Day at Ad Club 5/1/68; Miriam Goodman 1976; Dick Graffis 1969; Elma Greer; Russ Hodges (some autographed); Lon Simmons, preshow Giants, 8/64, etc.; Happy Days promo (baseball game feat. KSFO versus cast of TV show); Hamm's; Hastings; Hawaii promo 1973; Giants Billboard sponsors 1966; Giants game slides (from mail-in contest?); Bill Heyward; Pat Hilliard 1967; Rod Hussey 1972; Kava; Herb Kennedy, Night Sounds 1965; Don Klein; Terry McGovern; Ski Weekend 2/11/72; Gordy Soltar 1972; Sports Misc.- Hodges, Simmons, Thompson, Feeney; Stu Smith; Stanford 1969; Police Athletic League (PAL) Games 1961-, 1962, 1964, 1965, 1968, 1969, 1976; Russ Syracuse, Love Line; San Francisco Pix, Airshots 1967; Timebuyers Party 1972; Fr. Miles Riley 5/75; Rally de la Radio 11/21/73; Sears and Roebuck 1974; Scott Beach 1973; Sunshine Boys 1976; Toys For Tots 1976, 1977; United Crusades - KSFO Under Glass: Roos/Atkins 1960, Eichler Atrium, Union Square 1964 (also known as Wayzgoose, Squantum, and Turnerfest), 10/1970; Whaleboat Race 1965, 1966; Waters Helicopter; KYA, K-Lite Billboards 1981-1982, misc. picture folder; KYA Prom Night 4/15/83 (includes Bobby Freeman, etc.)
  - Oversized photographs and contact sheets (Box 36, Box 39)
  - Slides:Giants, marketing presentations, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    Four carousels of slides with accompanying audiocassettes. Three are Giants Pre-Post Commentary Presentations 1977-1978, and one is a presentation on marketing.
  - Slides: 29 small boxes of miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Slides: SF City Shots, Jim Brown Media Presentation, Giants Pre/Post 1975, 1977, 1978, etc., 1975-1978 (Box 35)
- Series 4. Ephemera
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1983 (Box 25)
    KSFO Program Schedules and Rate Cards 1956-1970; Program Logs 1960-1976; Biographies and Program Profiles, 1960s; Success Story Campaign and other marketing; KSFO, KYA, K-Lite stickers; KYA magnet; loose notes from recordings; Jan and Dean puzzle, etc.
  - Scrapbooks, 1960-1973 (Box 38, Box 37, Box 36, Box 39)
    Eight large scrapbooks containing published material, including proofs, posters, stickers, invitations, photographs, reprints, stationery, coverage maps, rate cards, and program guides. Most items concern the advertising and marketing of the station, especially involving disc jockeys and sports coverage. Most scrapbooks include material from the Success Story campaign, but other promotional campaigns include the Voyage to Nowhere, the Coincidental Horticulture Contest, the Dumb Contest, as well as benefits such as the Police Athletic League games and the United Crusades.